A Guide to the Kathryn H. Stone Papers
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #10555-b
Kathryn H. Stone Papers 1906-1993
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
10555-b
ca. 760 items
Suzanne Stone
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
This collection was made a gift to the Library by Ms. Suzanne Stone (daughter of Kathryn H. Stone), of Narberth, Pennsylvania, on August 10, 1994.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of ca. 760 items, 1906(1943-1982)1993, concerning Kathryn H. Stone and her involvement in the Gray Commission, the Greater Washington Research Center, the League of Women Voters, the planning of Reston, Virginia, and Virginia politics. There is a scrapbook, November 1955 -July 1956, of papers and newspaper clippings, pertaining to Virginia public schools, chiefly the Gray Commission and the desegregation issue. The loose papers and newspaper clippings were removed from the badly deteriorated scrapbook and foldered; the newspaper clippings were copied and discarded. League of Women Voters material includes correspondence, writings on the LWV and its history, memoranda, and printed material. There is also correspondence and papers of Anna Lord Strauss, and biographical material on Strauss and Lucretia Mott. Among the miscellaneous material on Women's Issues is a travel journal (electrostatic copy) of Alice Ilchman, titled "Fellow Travellers: The Ilchmans in Russia, Winter, 1987-1988." There are also several writings by Kathryn Stone concerning women's issues: "Women as Citizens" (1947); "Statement of Mrs. Kathryn H. Stone" (1965) prepared for the American Association of University Women; "Modernizing Government for a New Virginia" (1965); "The New Lib in Perspective," convocation address for Hood College(1970); "The 'New Lib' Through the Ages" 1970; and, other brief essays.
Container List
- Biographical Sketches of Kathryn H. and Harold A. Stone, and related material, 1906 (1961-1984) 1992 (Box Box 1)
- Correspondence of Kathryn H. and Harold A. Stone, 1932-1993 (Box Box 1)
- General Assembly Documents, 1963-1965 (Box Box 1)
- The Gray Commission: Correspondence and Papers (from Scrapbook), 1955 Dec-1956 Jul (Box Box 1)
- The Gray Commission: Newspaper Clippings (from Scrapbook), 1955 Nov-1956 Jul (Box Box 1)
- Greater Washington Research Center, 1980-1982 (Box Box 1)
- Greater Washington Research Center: Reports, 1980-1982 (Box Box 1)
- League of Women Voters, 1945-1993 (Box Box 1)
- League of Women Voters: Memorandum and other Comments, 1943-1946; (3 folders) (Box Box 2)
- League of Women Voters: Lucretia Mott, 1947-1981 (Box Box 2)
- League of Women Voters: Pamphlets, 1920-1950 (Box Box 2)
- League of Women Voters: Anna Lord Strauss--Correspondence, (1948-1952) 1982 (Box Box 2)
- League of Women Voters: Anna Lord Strauss--Memoranda, 1944-1960 (Box Box 2)
- League of Women Voters: Anna Lord Strauss--Photographs, 1951-1970 (Box Box 2)
- League of Women Voters: Anna Lord Strauss--Printed, 1948-1980 (Box Box 2)
- Political: Printed, 1929 (1959-1991) (Box Box 2)
- Quotations used for Opening Remarks of Speeches, ca. 1960s (Box Box 3)
- Reston, Virginia, 1962-1978 (Box Box 3)
- Virginia State and Local Campaigns and Elections, 1951-1959; (2 folders) (Box Box 3)
- Women's Issues, 1951-1993; (2 folders) (Box Box 3)
- Women's Issues: Reports of the President's Commission on the Status of Women, 1963-1966 (Box Box 3)
- Women's Issues: Writings by Kathryn H. Stone, 1947-1981 (Box Box 3)
- Youth Issues: Printed, 1959-1989 (Box Box 3)